GDPR Privacy Policy for [feddit.de](http://feddit.de/), a Federated Lemmy Instance
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Effective Date: 08.08.2023

Thank you for using [feddit.de](http://feddit.de/) (referred to as “we”, “our”, or “us”). This Privacy Policy outlines how we collect, use, disclose, and safeguard your personal data in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and other applicable data protection laws. By using our federated Lemmy instance, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

**1\. Information We Collect**

We may collect and process the following types of personal data:

* **Account Information**: When you create an account on our federated Lemmy instance, we may collect your username, email address (optional), and password.
    
* **Usage Data**: We collect information about your interactions with our platform, including posts, comments, votes, and community memberships.
    
* **Device Information**: We may collect information about the device you use to access our platform, such as IP address, browser type, operating system, and device identifiers.

**2\. How We Use Your Information**

We use your personal data for the following purposes:

* **Account Management**: To create and manage your account, provide customer support, and communicate with you about your account.
    
* **Platform Operation**: To operate, improve, and maintain our federated Lemmy instance, including troubleshooting, data analysis, and research.
    
* **Communication**: To send you updates, notifications, and administrative messages related to our platform.
    
* **Community Interaction**: To enable interactions with other users, posts, and communities on our federated Lemmy instance.

**3\. Data Sharing and Disclosure**

We may share your personal data in the following ways:

* **With Other Users**: Your interactions on our federated Lemmy instance, such as posts, comments, and votes, are visible to other users in accordance with Lemmy’s federated architecture (see 4.).
    
* **With Service Providers**: We may share your personal data with third-party service providers who assist us in operating our platform.
    
* **Legal Compliance**: We may disclose your personal data if required by law or to protect our rights, privacy, safety, or property, as well as that of our users and the public.

**4\. Data Transfer to Other Instances**

Our federated Lemmy instance operates on a decentralized model, which means that data may be transferred to and shared with other instances within the Fediverse network. This is an inherent feature of the Lemmy platform’s architecture, designed to allow users to interact with content and users across different instances while maintaining control over their data.

When you create an account, post content, comment, or engage in any activity on [feddit.de](http://feddit.de/), some of your data may be replicated and shared with other instances through a process called federation. This allows users from various instances to view and interact with your content, comments, and activities.

It’s important to understand that when your data is federated, it remains subject to the privacy policies and terms of use of both [feddit.de](http://feddit.de/) and the instance to which it is shared. We do not have direct control over how other instances handle your data, and their data protection practices may vary.

We recommend that you review the privacy policies and terms of use of the instances you interact with to understand how your data may be used, shared, and protected. While we strive to promote responsible data handling and protection within the Fediverse network, it’s essential to be aware of the decentralized nature of the platform and its implications for data transfer.

By using [feddit.de](http://feddit.de/), you acknowledge and consent to the possibility of your data being transferred to other instances as part of the federation process. If you have concerns about data transfer or data protection, please feel free to contact us, and we will do our best to address your inquiries.

**5\. Data Retention**

We will retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy or as required by law. You may request the deletion of your account and associated data from this instance at any time.

**6\. Your Rights**

You have the right to:

* Access and rectify your personal data.
* Withdraw your consent at any time.
* Request the erasure of your personal data.
* Object to the processing of your personal data.
* Lodge a complaint with a data protection authority.

**7\. Security**

We take reasonable measures to protect your personal data from unauthorized access, alteration, or disclosure. However, no data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed as completely secure.

**8\. Contact Us**

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or our data practices, please contact us at [@wintermute@feddit.de](https://feddit.de/u/wintermute) / [pgcn5lz86@relay.firefox.com](mailto:pgcn5lz86@relay.firefox.com).

Please note that this Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. Please check back regularly for any updates.

By using [feddit.de](http://feddit.de/), you acknowledge that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy and consent to the processing of your personal data as described herein.
